# 哈喽大家好我是王刚 本期视频我给大家分享一道家常菜
Hello everyone, I am Wang Gang
# 本期视频我给大家分享一道家常菜
Today I will share with you how to make
# 干煸肥肠
Ganbian Feichang
(Dry-Fried Pork Intestine)
# 首先我们准备新鲜的肥肠1套
First prepare a set of fresh pork intestine
# 即一头猪的大肠就是1套
That is, the entire large intestine of a pig
# 然后选择肠头这段比较光滑的一节用剪刀剪断备用
Then choose the smoother part of the pork intestine and cut it off with scissors
# 嫌麻烦的同学也可以任意选择
Also feel free to choose any part that you like
# 大家一直以来都有个疑问
It's commonly asked that
# 就是大肠到底那一面才是接触粪便
which side of the intestine is in contact with the feces
# 其实就是在大肠光滑的这一面接触猪的粪便
In fact, it is the smoother side of the intestine that is in contact with the feces
# 因为摊主的清理肥肠的时候
Because when sellers clean the intestine
# 通常会将带粪便这面翻过来清洗干净
they usually flip it over and clean the side with feces
# 摊主为了有好的卖相
As sellers may want a better presence for selling
# 所以会将有猪油的一面隐藏在里面
they would hide the side with lard
# 下一步开始处理
Next we start processing
# 我们加入适量的清水先将光滑的一面抓洗几遍
First add some water and wash the smooth side several times
# 然后用剪刀将肥肠剪开再撕掉里面多余的肥油
Then use scissors to cut the intestine and tear off the excess fat from the inside
# 喜欢味道浓一些的同学也可以适当的保留一些
Those who prefer a stronger taste can also keep some fat
# 下一步继续清洗
Next we continue washing
# 盆中加入1小把食用盐
Add some salt to the pot
# 再加入适量的白醋抓洗10分钟
Then add some white vinegar and wash for 10 minutes
# 这一步的目的是去除肥肠的异味
The purpose of this step is to remove the odor of the intestine
# 10分钟之后加入适量的清水清洗干净
After 10 minutes add some water to wash it up
# 然后将肥肠切成小段挤干水分备用
Then cut the intestine into small pieces and squeeze out the excess water for use
# 挤干水分之后加入适量的生抽酱油抓匀
After squeezing out the water add some light soy sauce and mix evenly
# 加生抽的目的是提前入味
The purpose of adding soy sauce is to season in advance
# 然后加入1大把干淀粉抓匀
Then add a large amount of dry starch and mix evenly
# 下一步开始准备辅料
Next we start preparing the side ingredients
# 准备1小块生姜和几颗大蒜切成粒备用
Prepare a small piece of ginger and a few garlics and cut into small cubes for use
# 准备几根小葱切成小段备用
Prepare a few scallions and cut into small pieces for use
# 准备适量的干辣椒剪成小节备用
Prepare some dried chilis and cut into small pieces for use
# 最后准备适量的油酥花生米和芝麻备用
Lastly prepare some fried peanuts and sesame seeds for use
# 下一步开始制作
Next we start cooking
# 首先我们把锅烧热
First heat the wok
# 锅烧热之后加入宽油
After the wok is heated, add in "Kuan You"
("wide/broad oil" aka a large amount of oil)
# 油温烧至6成热之后将准备好的肥肠依次下锅炸至定型
When the oil is 60% heated, put the prepared intestine piece by piece into the wok and deep fry to shape
# 肥肠炸至定型之后捞出
After the intestine is fried to shape, take it out from the wok
# 然后将油温重新升至7成热再下肥肠复炸
Then re-heat the oil to 70% and then deep fry the intestine for the second time
# 待肥肠金黄酥脆之后捞出备用
After the intestine turns golden and crispy, take it out from the wok for use
# 然后将热油到处下一步开始炒制
Then pour out the heated oil and start stir frying
# 过中加入少许的热油
Add a little bit of heated oil to the wok
# 加入适量的青花椒爆锅
Then fry some Sichuan green pepper in the wok
# 再讲准备好的姜蒜粒下锅爆香
Then fry the prepared ginger and garlic in the wok until aromatic
# 料头爆香之后加入炸好的肥肠翻炒几下
After that, add the fried intestine and stir fry a few times
# 翻炒几下之后加入准备好的干辣椒下锅
After a few times of stir frying, add the prepared dried chilis to the pan
# 然后在锅边淋入少许的葱油开小火翻炒1分钟
Then pour a little bit of scallion oil from the side of the wok and stir fry for one minute with low heat
# 这一步的目的是将干辣椒炒香炒出辣味
The purpose of this step is to extract the aroma and spiciness of the dried chilis
# 1分钟之后加入花生米和芝麻然后开始调味
After one minute add the dried peanuts and sesame seeds and start seasoning
# 锅中加入适量的鸡精
Add some chicken broth powder to the wok
# 加入少许白糖
Add a little bit of sugar
# 再加入少许香油翻炒几下
Then add a little bit of sesame oil and stir fry a few times
# 最后加入小葱炒匀即可出锅装盘
Finally add the scallions and stir fry evenly to serve in plate
# 一道香辣开胃的干煸肥肠就制作完成
A spicy and appetizing dish, "Ganbian Feichang" (dry fried pork intestine), is now ready
# 下面开始技术总结
Next we do a technical summary
# 第一，肥肠最好选择肠头的位置，这样成菜更有口感
First, it is best to choose the smooth part of pig intestine, so that the final dish has a better texture
# 第二，肥肠需要提前用生抽调味，否则炒制的时候无法入味
Second, the intestine needs to be seasoned in advance with soy sauce, otherwise it will be less flavorful after it’s fried
# 第三，此菜更适合开胃下酒，不适合下饭
Third, this dish is better as an appetizer or to go with alcohol, but is less suitable to go with rice
# 干煸肥肠的技术总结完毕
The technique summary of Ganbian Feichang is complete
# 关注西瓜视频美食作家王刚
Subscribe to "Gourmet Chef Wang Wang"
# 这里总有一款属于你的菜
where there's always a dish for you